Bay Area, CA | tess.elle@proton.me | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tessbakke/ | https://tesslins.com/

## **SUMMARY**

I am a full stack software engineer with a strong background building tools and websites to create and serve experiences at both small and large scales. Things I like include: combining the human & the technical, examining & understanding complexity, and learning & teaching.

## TECH SKILLS

- Languages: Typescript & Javascript with Node, Python
- Frontend frameworks: React, Vue, Serverless framework, Angular
- CMSs: Shopify, Squarespace, Wordpress
- Databases & datastores: MongoDB, Postgres, MySQL, Redis
- Amazon Web Services: Elastic Transcoder, Lambda, S3, SNS
- Tools: Docker, Jenkins, JIRA, Git/Github, npm, Webpack, Puppet, Unix, Terraform
- Servers: Experience working with both cloud services and physical servers (mostly co-located with some on-prem)

## PROJECT SKILLS

- Communicating and building consensus among technical and non-technical stakeholders
- Scoping and project management
- Mentoring & encouraging team-wide learning and skill-sharing
- Focusing on work from an end product perspective

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2023-present | Web consultant (Bay Area, CA & remote)

Helping people create or improve space online for their work, products or ideas by building or supporting Shopify, Squarespace, or Wordpress sites.

### 2022-2023 | Senior Software Engineer II at Vox Media (San Francisco, CA)

Fullstack individual contributor building a custom payments layer for subscription podcasts & newsletters using Stripe for payments with a Postgres database, Typescript backend, and React frontend.

#### 2021 | **Senior Software Engineering Manager** at Kink.com (San Francisco, CA)

Engineering team manager providing technical and product oversight to seven engineers

2017-2021 | **Software Engineering Lead** at Kink.com (San Francisco, CA)

Full stack individual contributor & manager of a team of 2-4 engineers creating a partially serverless internal publishing system built on Amazon Web Services plus a corresponding CMS with a Vue frontend and Node.js backend.

2015 - 2017 | **Software Engineer** at Kink.com (San Francisco, CA)

Fullstack individual contributor to a high-traffic, subscription-based, media-streaming website. Large projects included integrating a new payment provider and updating the billing workflow.

## 2014-2015 | Web Engineer at AgileMD (San Francisco, CA)

Individual contributor to the frontend of a Backbone.js web application for creating, customizing, and distributing interactive documents

## 2011-2104 | Cofounder at Skylight Scope (Oakland, CA)

Co-founder of a start-up design solution delivering low cost digital microscopy solutions to healthcare and education markets through our first commercial product, a universal smartphone to microscope adapter.

2013-2104 | **Geologist & Project Manager** at BESST, Inc. (San Rafael, CA) 2013 | **Resident Naturalist** at University of Georgia (Monteverde, Costa Rica) 2009-2012 | **Assistant Geologist** at Holguin, Fahan & Associates (Pleasanton, CA)

# **EDUCATION**

2014 | Software Engineering Fellow at Hackbright Academy (San Francisco, CA) 2003-2007 | BS in Earth Science at University of California, Santa Cruz (Santa Cruz, CA)